<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://esivy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://esivy.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-08T03:42:33+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">E.S. Ivy</title><subtitle>The blog of E.S. Ivy, author of the Miri Attwater series and MomBehindtheCurtain.com</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Test</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/test/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test" /><published>2020-05-12T04:11:26+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-12T04:11:26+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/test</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/test/">&lt;p&gt;This is a test, huh. Interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a test, huh. Interesting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3764</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/3764/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3764" /><published>2018-05-24T17:55:52+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-24T17:55:52+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/3764</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/3764/"></content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Netflix The Crown - the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/netflix-the-crown-duke-of-windsor-wallis-simpson/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Netflix The Crown - the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson" /><published>2017-02-07T18:19:36+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T18:19:36+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/netflix-the-crown-duke-of-windsor-wallis-simpson</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/netflix-the-crown-duke-of-windsor-wallis-simpson/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80025678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3571&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/The-Crown-Netflix.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor - bachground history. How Elizabeth II came to the throne after the abdication of the Duke of Windsor - The Crown - Netflix&quot; width=&quot;674&quot; height=&quot;1000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was surprised at first that there was so much about the Duke of Windsor in the Netflix series' The Crown, since the crown is mainly about the reign of Queen Elizabeth II. The abdication of King Edward VIII happened long before Queen Elizabeth II came to the throne. However, a lot of things that happened early in the reign of&amp;nbsp;Queen Elizabeth II were caused by&amp;nbsp;the crisis when her uncle abdicated. Knowing a bit more about the history of how a former king became the Duke of Windsor might give you a new understanding of the treatment of his story in Netflix The Crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/JWtnJjn6ng0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;My mother had a fascination with the British monarchy that started in her childhood. She also likes to read (and understatement) and would entertain us with stories from history she had read. So I knew from her that Queen Elizabeth II was only Queen&amp;nbsp;because her uncle gave up the throne to marry an American divorcee.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The way I understood it, when King George V died, the Duke of Windsor was supposed to inherit the throne, but he decided he wanted to marry an American woman who had been divorced. The laws said he couldn't marry her and be king. So he said, &quot;Okay, I won't be King then.&quot; He gave up the throne and that was that. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;He never looked back and never regretted it. He moved off the pages of history and his brother and niece, Queen Elizabeth II, moved on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The full story is way more complicated!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I read about the evolution of the British Monarchy, I discovered that he hadn't disappeared after all. In fact, during WWII there were rumors about the Duke of Windsor plotting with Hitler to put the Duke back on the throne. I began to think that studying his biography might provide some interesting motivation and actions for some characters in my children&amp;rsquo;s fantasy series that included royalty. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2kBpjqI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Miri Attwater Mermaid Princess series.&lt;/a&gt;) In any case, it was a convenient excuse to read some interesting history!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Different books give different views of &amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; I started with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;King Edward VIII: A Biography&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; by Philip Ziegler. Then I decided to read a second, because it bothers me that an author is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;always&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; biased. Sometimes intentionally, sometimes not. And how can I come to an honest conclusion for myself if I don't consider different sides? So I decided to read another book just to get another point of view. And oh, while I'm at it, I'm not sure which book will be the best, so I'll just check out everything the library has and read what I want. And before I knew it I had read not one book on the Duke of Windsor, but six. (For a full list and links, see below.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Ridiculous, I know. What need do I have to be an authority on the Duke of Windsor? But along the way I also gained interesting insights into how World War II came about the maneuvering of royalty and government. I was impressed by how personal lives can affect the direction of almost the entire world. Following is a summary of what seemed to me to be the interesting points about the Duke of Windsor's life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to follow British Royal Titles when reading about&amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Technically, when you write about royalty, your are supposed to use the correct title for people for the period of time you are covering. This means that the same person can be referred to with multiple different names in the same book, even the same paragraph! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The full names and titles for the Duke of Windsor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you were to read an official biography about Edward Albert Christian George Andrew Patrick David, he would be referred to as &quot;David&quot; by his family and in the book during his childhood. As he got older he would also temporarily be called the Prince of Wales, while his father George V is on the throne. Then he is temporarily King Edward the VIII. And finally he's the Duke of Windsor after his abdication. Just to confuse you more, early in the book his father and grandfather would also be called the Prince of Wales at different times. So, to keep things simple, &amp;nbsp;I will continually refer to him as the Duke of Windsor. That's the title he held at his death.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A short history of&amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Abdication of the Duke of Windsor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To begin with, the Duke of Windsor didn't give up the throne &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;before&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; he became King. He already &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;was&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; King and had been King for several months. But he did give up the throne before he was &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;crowned &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;king. The Duke of Windsor automatically became King on the death of his father, King George V. Modern coronations being what they are, you can't organize one in a week. It takes a little more than a year. So he was King Edward VIII, for a little less than a year before he abdicated and give up the throne.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wallis Simpson, a married woman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke of Windsor also didn't abdicate to marry a divorced American woman. He gave up his crown to marry a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;married&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; woman, Wallis Simpson. Her divorce was in process when he abdicated, but Mrs. Simpson (as she came to be known) was still married. Okay, technically I guess she was already &quot;a divorced woman&quot; because this was her second marriage. She'd already been divorced once. But the point is that the whole time they were dating, or courting, or whatever you want to call it, Wallis Simpson was married. In fact, the Duke of Windsor had a history of dating married women.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke of Windsor and his birthright&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Let me back up and try to explain briefly how the Duke of Windsor got into that situation. The Duke of Windsor grew up knowing he was destined to be King, but wondering if that's what he wanted, or even if he was qualified.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;His letters and diaries show that he questioned his right to rule just because of his birth. Being brought up separate from others, with a difficult father who was King, wasn't easy. When he served in World War II, he didn't think it was fair that his fellow soldiers had to endure the trenches and other horrors of war when he wasn't allowed to put himself in any danger. At the same time, he couldn't fathom how French soldiers could follow an officer who was of lower birth rank than they were. He wrestled with a conscious that was developing differently from the way he was raised. After the war, the poor and destitute who couldn't find work in Britain troubled him, but he had few ideas (and in fact, probably little power) to do anything about it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The many married women of the Duke of Windsor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Meanwhile, both of the Duke of Windsor's serious relationships were with married women. This wasn't uncommon among the nobles he was surrounded by. At a time when it was difficult for women to hold jobs and make money of their own, marriages were often their &quot;careers.&quot; They were the means to consolidate or preserve wealth. When the nobles in Britain started running out of money, newly wealthy American girls crossed the Atlantic and married for a tiara in exchange for a fortune that helped their husbands hold onto the family estate. Everyone thus having done their duty, no one saw any reason why they shouldn't have a little fun afterward. Courting before the marriage was a business negotiation. Dating after marriage was the romance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The difference was that the Duke always wanted to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;marry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; the married woman he was &quot;dating.&quot; He thought it was dishonorable not to. Until Wallis Simpson, neither of the British married women he dated let him get very far with that thought. They understood too well that it would not only jeopardize his position, but threaten the stability of the country. They probably also didn't want to spoil the fun.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The history of Wallis Simpson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Mrs. Simpson grew up dependent on an uncle to support her and her widowed mother. While no one, including herself, ever called Mrs. Simpson beautiful, she was elegant, intelligent, and had a talent for showing true interest in men. She never lacked for suitors. Sadly, her first husband turned out to be to an abusive alcoholic. She finally got her marriage dissolved on grounds of abandonment. Not long after her first divorce, she married her second husband, Ernest Simpson. He wasn't rich, but he was well off and steady in temperament.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke of Windsor meets Wallis Simpson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;When the Duke was introduced to the Simpsons by friends, the Simpsons were happily married. As a British subject with an American background, Ernest Simpson was thrilled to be in the circle of royalty. It didn't hurt that it helped his business connections. Wallis Simpson thoroughly enjoyed entertaining as part of high society, and the Duke admired a woman who didn't just bow and cater to his every need. He considered that kind of adoration false, and I would guess may be one of the reasons married women were more appealing. They probably weren't as eager to please him as a girl who was trying to catch and marry him.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke became devoted to Mrs. Simpson and her lack of fear to give him guidance. Mrs. Simpson became enamored with the lifestyle of luxury and gifts of jewels. She seems to have thought that the Duke's infatuation would run it's course, just like it had with other married women. If she played her cards right she'd have acquired enough gifts for a little security when he moved on, and she and Mr. Simpson would go back to their married life a little more financially secure.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Only the Duke was more devoted than usual. He abruptly cut off all ties to his former mistresses, who had been close to him for years, and became fairly isolated. There were some interesting dynamics between the the Duke and Wallis, reported differently depending on who's doing the observing. But by several accounts, and for the rest of his life, the Duke would light up and become more sure of himself whenever Wallis was near. When she was gone, he was dejected and depressed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke of Windsor becomes King&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But maybe more importantly, the turning point in their relationship may have come when his father died. The Duke of Windsor (as he would come to be known later) was now King Edward VIII of Great Britain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But unlike the summary suggests, he didn't just say, &quot;Oh, oops, well I want to marry an already married woman so I'll just step aside and you can put my brother on the throne.&quot; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;It was to prove to be a long year for both the British Royalty and Parliament.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;At first, the Duke seemed to honestly believe that it wouldn't matter to the people whether or not Mrs. Simpson was a divorcee. As the Prince of Wales, he was extremely popular with the public and didn't think anything he did would change their love of him. After all, all of the nobles he was surrounded with fooled around. They even divorced and remarried pretty frequently.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Problem with Wallis Simpson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But as Anne Sheba perhaps explained the best in her book, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;That Woman, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;that blase view didn't apply to most of the population. One of the reasons that divorces were still difficult to obtain in Britain was that with no careers, women usually had no means of support other than a husband. So it was the women who were against Wallis Simpson divorcing even more than the men. The way they saw it, was if the King married a divorced woman, divorce would become more acceptable, and women would be the ones left destitute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The negotiations to marry Wallis Simpson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke argued and negotiated with men in government, and men not in government but still in power (such as Winston Churchill), for months. His brother, the future King George V (father of Elizabeth II) didn't want to be King. The possibility of the Duke marrying Mrs. Simpson, but her not getting a title and their children not becoming heirs, was considered and discarded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to remember that all this was going on as Hitler was flaunting the power of Nazi Germany. So in addition to dealing with that, the British government was distracted by their King's romance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;It appears that for her part, Mrs. Simpson wanted things to just go on as they were and eventually things would move on one way or the other. She had no real desire to be Queen per say, but she found it impossible to give up the luxury and jewels that her relationship with the Duke gave her.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The longer they argued, the more extreme the Duke became. In the end he refused to be crowned unless he could marry Mrs. Simpson before the coronation and have her crowned Queen with him. The longer the argument drug on, the uncertainty started to be a drain on the economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;On top of that, it truly was a constitutional crisis. From this vantage point, with the British monarchy not having any real power, this seems hard to believe. There wren't many kings and queens left after World War I; the British monarchy was a survivor, and barely hanging on.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The fall of European Monarchies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;At the beginning of the 1900's there were monarchies all over Europe. Now, after World War I - still being called the Great War - the global map looked very different. At the time the Duke of Windsor was arguing to marry Wallis Simpson, it was just a few years after most of the royalty of Europe had toppled. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Many of them were assassinated. And through Queen Victoria's huge family, many - if not most - of them were related to the British Royal family, such as the last German Kaiser, Wilhelm II. The Duke himself had personally met a number of his European royal relatives who'd met their fate. This included the Russian Tsar, whose entire family was brutally murdered. This happened after the Tsar's cousin - the Duke's father, King George V - refused him asylum in Britain. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The toppling of monarchies all over Europe had proven that popular opinion could threaten stability, dissolve a monarchy, and worse. And both the royal family and the government of Britain knew it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke of Windsor Abdicates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The argument grew so public that there were threats on Mrs. Simpson's life. She fled to France to stay with friends. In the Duke's defense, part of his decision to not back down was because he believed the woman he was in love with would be ruined, personally and socially, if he deserted her at this point. But he also was personally miserable without her near. He made up his mind abdicate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Still, there were lots of details to be ironed out. What would the Duke now be called? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;His brother created the new title of Duke of Windsor for him. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;How would he be paid? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Where would he live? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;A lot of things were discussed, but in the rising panic of the moment, not everything was decided for certain before he left Britain.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor give up the throne to live in &quot;poverty&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In due course Mrs. Simpson's divorce became final, the Duke's brother was crowned King, and the Duke and Duchess were married. But a lot of bad feelings remained. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke's family was upset that he gave up his responsibilities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;King George VI was upset that during his negotiations for his allowance, the Duke had misled him about how much money he had. (&amp;ldquo;A lot&amp;rdquo; in most people's terms. &amp;ldquo;Not enough&amp;rdquo; in his way of thinking. There is also evidence that he had already transferred most of his cash into Mrs. Simpson's name.) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;It was decided (by someone, it's not clear who) that even though the Duke would still be known as His Royal Highness the Duke of Windsor, his wife would simply be the Duchess of Windsor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Being offended by the refusal of allowing the Duchess to be called officially &amp;ldquo;Her Royal Highness&amp;rdquo; is probably only completely understood by royalty, and perhaps by nobles. But to the Duke, who ironically on one hand didn't think rank by birth was fair, but was raised in the tradition, it was the ultimate insult. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;So there was tension between the Duke, his family, and the British government.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke of Windsor and Hitler&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Based on his experience in WWI, the Duke thought that getting into any war was the greatest folly. He wasn't alone in thinking that Hitler and Germany should be negotiated with. He thought that Hitler was the only thing standing against the Russian communists and the rest of Europe, and that going against the Fascists would doom the rest of the world to communism. As it turns out, that opinion was right in a lot of ways.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;When a friend arranged for the Duke to visit Germany and observe what Hitler had done for the poor, working conditions, and housing, he jumped at the chance. If the Duchess couldn't be a Royal Highness, it gave him an opportunity to take her on what amounted to a royal tour, and also to study ways in which the poor could be helped. He naively didn't think it endorsed the atrocities of the Nazis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor and World War II&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;When war did break out, he was disappointed when Britain joined in, but wanted to serve. A place was finally found for him in France, but there was a lot of confusion when France was invaded. The Duke and Duchess fled but couldn't immediately get off the continent. This is where contradictions and entanglement with Germans really start to complicate things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke and Duchess worried about what would become of their possessions in France. Through German friends, they possibly arranged to make sure their possessions stayed safe. (The Duke had a lot of relatives among the Germans. Queen Victoria's husband, Prince Albert, was German.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The plot by the Nazis to crown the Duke of Windsor King of Great Britain&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Germans plotted to kidnap the Duke. They thought that when they invaded England, if they put him on the throne his past popularity would help them. There are a lot of documents to support this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke and Duchess seemed to not know anything about the plot. But they balked at a &quot;suitable position&quot; not being found for the Duke. Then when he was offered the office of Governor of the Bahamas, not only was it still not good enough, but they balked over rumors started by the Germans that the British government itself was out to kill them during or before the trip.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor&amp;nbsp;and the rest of World War II&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Eventually a friend and adviser &amp;nbsp;convinced them to sail. During the course of the war they continued to harass Winston Churchill and the King about the Duchess' title, their allowance, and money for other matters, which seemed rather selfish given the current world crisis. They took frequent and sometimes overly long trips to the United States and embarrassed the British government by some of their opinions on the war. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;But maybe it was was a diversion (if not a nice one) for King George VI and Churchill from the even more depressing war. And other than that, the Duke and Duchess worked hard at their new positions. He made some progress with equalizing pay and government reform. She worked for the Red Cross and other relief efforts for the war and the poor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor after World War II&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;After the war, the Duke still wanted a position. The Royal family and the government still didn't want to raise the rank of the Duchess to Her Royal Highness. The Queen (then Queen Elizabeth, later known as the Queen Mother) feared that the Duke's old popularity would overshadow King George VI, and all their family's sacrifice for him to be King during the war would be discarded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke refused to return to live in Britain if his wife wasn't raised to the same rank as him. On top of that, he still considered himself destitute (even he was a multi-millionaire, by any standard) and if he returned to Britain he would have to pay taxes, the ultimate insult.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duke and Duchess settled in France, but they spent almost half of every year in the United States. Having discarded their own royalty centuries before (starting with Marie Antoinette's husband), France was now a haven for discarded royalty of other countries. France didn't require the Duke and Duchess to pay taxes, provided personal security, and eventually gave them a mansion in Paris almost rent free.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In the minds of the Duke and Duchess, the Duke - as a former King and still royalty - had to live at a certain standard to which he had become accustomed. He didn't even know how to pack his own suitcase, after all. They considered themselves poor and were always afraid of running out of money, but bought luxury items and kept a staff that seemed to be at odds with that. (See &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Jewels of the Duchess of Windsor,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; by John Culme and Nicholas Rayner, to get an idea of what I mean. That really makes their wealth concrete.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Duke and Duchess of Windsor, a great love story?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Some accounts have them as miserable with their lack of royal position, citing letters. Other accounts, some by friends, say they were happy with their life of luxury, travel, entertaining, golf, and gardening. The truth probably lies somewhere in the middle. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Their letters were probably mostly written when they were trying to negotiate. Often people complain about things they don't like, but don't take the time to write about things that are going well. If you only read the letters, you might get a skewed perspective. On the other hand, there are friends who you wouldn't tell your complaints to. By all accounts the Duke remained devoted to the Duchess and she, if not devoted, remained loyal to him. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Letters to her second husband, though, suggests she never wanted the divorce, she just wanted to have some &quot;fun&quot; for awhile.&amp;nbsp;Perhaps she would have been happiest as mistress of a king. Some stories seemed to indicate that while the Duke always worshiped her, there were times she just barely tolerated him. But she either had the decency, or fear of social downfall, to stick by him once he gave up everything for her. That in itself is admirable. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Commitment is what keeps marriages going for the long haul, after all. Maybe the definition of a great romance isn't happily ever after, but the length of the ever after. By that definition, the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson did have a great romance.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who's to blame for the abdication?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;As I read about the quibbles after the abdication, one of the things that bothered me was the constant refrain of the Duke and Duchess that they hadn't done anything wrong. I won't even go into the list of possibilities and argue the points. But in the last book I read, something struck me that none of the authors pointed out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;After his abdication, the Duke gave a speech on the radio. It's famous for the line &quot;... I have found it impossible to carry the heavy burden of responsibility and to discharge my duties as King ... without the support of the woman I love...&quot; But it also contains these lines.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;There has never been any constitutional difference between me and [the Ministers of the Crown] and between me and Parliament. Bred in the constitutional tradition by my Father,&lt;strong&gt; I should never have allowed any such issue to arise.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;(emphasis mine)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In the end, the Duke of Windsor abdicated when it became clear that his personal decision was leading to the instability of the government. But unlike his brother, King George VI, he wasn't willing to give up personal happiness for his country. And maybe he couldn't. But at least once, and publicly, he was willing to acknowledge his mistake.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Newly unclassified documents show that the government of Great Britain was sorried enough that Wallis Simpson might be a spy and the fascist leaning of the then King Edward VIII that they wire-tapped the King's phone. You can read more about it in the article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/british-spies-tapped-king-edward-s-phone-eavesdrop-wallis-simpson-n741906&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;British Spies Tapped King Edward&amp;rsquo;s Phone to Eavesdrop on Wallis Simpson Calls.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The best books about the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;You may have noticed that this isn't a scholarly research paper. I haven't cited any sources, and the professional writer in me feels a little bit guilty about that. Without any footnotes or any authoritative sources (primary sources, meaning I haven&amp;rsquo;t researched original documents myself), you probably shouldn't believe a word you've read here. But here's a list of the books I've read:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you just want to read one book relatively short book, I suggest:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2eZ0o0s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3519&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/That-Woman.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;that woman - Wallis Simpson&quot; width=&quot;331&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;That Woman&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; by Anne Sebba.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you want to bring some of the setting and jewelry vividly to life, to get a sense of the riches of the &quot;impoverished&quot; Duke and Duchess of Windsor add:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fOZBOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3520&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Jewels-of-Duchess-of-Windsor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Jewels of the Duchess of Windsor, Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson&quot; width=&quot;369&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fOZBOA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Jewels of the Duchess of Windsor&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;By John Clume and Nicholas Rayner. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;If you want to read a more scholarly work, move on to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2eZ4K7L&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3510&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Edward-VIII.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Duke of Windsor biography - King Edwards VIII&quot; width=&quot;333&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2eZ4K7L&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;King Edward VIII: A Biography&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; by Philip Ziegler&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a naturally biased view, and the most difficult read, dig into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fP37Zb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3511&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/A-Kings-Story.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Duke of Windsor autobiography - A King's Story&quot; width=&quot;298&quot; height=&quot;475&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fP37Zb&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;A King's Story: The Memoirs of H.R.H. the Duke of Windsor K.G.&lt;/a&gt;, by the Duke of Windsor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Interesting how he titled his book not &quot;A Duke's Story,&quot; but &quot;A&lt;em&gt; King's&lt;/em&gt; Story.&quot; It gives you some insight into how he thought of himself and wanted to be seen.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Also scholarly, and easier to read but an older book, is:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fRfcMh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;alignnone&quot; style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3567&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/21TaQ0rqXrL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Duke of Windsor - The Windsor story&quot; width=&quot;107&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; /&gt;The Windsor Story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fRfcMh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; by J. Bryan III and Charles J.V. Murphy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Finally, for a different point of view read:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fP44AM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3569&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/duchess-of-windsor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;duchess of windsor&quot; width=&quot;311&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2fP44AM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Duchess of Windsor,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; by her friend, Diana Mosley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More About Netflix series - The Crown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/80025678&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Crown - Neflix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4786824/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Crown - Imdb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.townandcountrymag.com/society/tradition/news/a8741/the-crown-india-hicks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;Watching The Crown with Lady Pamela Hicks, Queen Elizabeth's Lady-in-Waiting - India Hicks shares her mother's memories of the true story behind the Netflix series.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://people.com/royals/the-crown-historically-accurate-netflix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;How Real Is the Crown? Fact-Checking the Series About Queen Elizabeth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vogue.com/article/the-crown-vs-real-life-royals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot;&gt;The Cast of The Crown vs. the Real-Life Royals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">I was surprised at first that there was so much about the Duke of Windsor in the Netflix series' The Crown, since the crown is mainly about the reign of Queen Elizabeth II. The abdication of King Edward VIII happened long before Queen Elizabeth II came to the throne. However, a lot of things that happened early in the reign of&amp;nbsp;Queen Elizabeth II were caused by&amp;nbsp;the crisis when her uncle abdicated. Knowing a bit more about the history of how a former king became the Duke of Windsor might give you a new understanding of the treatment of his story in Netflix The Crown. https://youtu.be/JWtnJjn6ng0 The Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson My mother had a fascination with the British monarchy that started in her childhood. She also likes to read (and understatement) and would entertain us with stories from history she had read. So I knew from her that Queen Elizabeth II was only Queen&amp;nbsp;because her uncle gave up the throne to marry an American divorcee. The way I understood it, when King George V died, the Duke of Windsor was supposed to inherit the throne, but he decided he wanted to marry an American woman who had been divorced. The laws said he couldn't marry her and be king. So he said, &quot;Okay, I won't be King then.&quot; He gave up the throne and that was that. He never looked back and never regretted it. He moved off the pages of history and his brother and niece, Queen Elizabeth II, moved on. The full story is way more complicated! As I read about the evolution of the British Monarchy, I discovered that he hadn't disappeared after all. In fact, during WWII there were rumors about the Duke of Windsor plotting with Hitler to put the Duke back on the throne. I began to think that studying his biography might provide some interesting motivation and actions for some characters in my children&amp;rsquo;s fantasy series that included royalty. (Miri Attwater Mermaid Princess series.) In any case, it was a convenient excuse to read some interesting history! Different books give different views of &amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson I started with King Edward VIII: A Biography by Philip Ziegler. Then I decided to read a second, because it bothers me that an author is always biased. Sometimes intentionally, sometimes not. And how can I come to an honest conclusion for myself if I don't consider different sides? So I decided to read another book just to get another point of view. And oh, while I'm at it, I'm not sure which book will be the best, so I'll just check out everything the library has and read what I want. And before I knew it I had read not one book on the Duke of Windsor, but six. (For a full list and links, see below.) Ridiculous, I know. What need do I have to be an authority on the Duke of Windsor? But along the way I also gained interesting insights into how World War II came about the maneuvering of royalty and government. I was impressed by how personal lives can affect the direction of almost the entire world. Following is a summary of what seemed to me to be the interesting points about the Duke of Windsor's life. How to follow British Royal Titles when reading about&amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson Technically, when you write about royalty, your are supposed to use the correct title for people for the period of time you are covering. This means that the same person can be referred to with multiple different names in the same book, even the same paragraph! The full names and titles for the Duke of Windsor If you were to read an official biography about Edward Albert Christian George Andrew Patrick David, he would be referred to as &quot;David&quot; by his family and in the book during his childhood. As he got older he would also temporarily be called the Prince of Wales, while his father George V is on the throne. Then he is temporarily King Edward the VIII. And finally he's the Duke of Windsor after his abdication. Just to confuse you more, early in the book his father and grandfather would also be called the Prince of Wales at different times. So, to keep things simple, &amp;nbsp;I will continually refer to him as the Duke of Windsor. That's the title he held at his death. A short history of&amp;nbsp;the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson The Abdication of the Duke of Windsor To begin with, the Duke of Windsor didn't give up the throne before he became King. He already was King and had been King for several months. But he did give up the throne before he was crowned king. The Duke of Windsor automatically became King on the death of his father, King George V. Modern coronations being what they are, you can't organize one in a week. It takes a little more than a year. So he was King Edward VIII, for a little less than a year before he abdicated and give up the throne. Wallis Simpson, a married woman The Duke of Windsor also didn't abdicate to marry a divorced American woman. He gave up his crown to marry a married woman, Wallis Simpson. Her divorce was in process when he abdicated, but Mrs. Simpson (as she came to be known) was still married. Okay, technically I guess she was already &quot;a divorced woman&quot; because this was her second marriage. She'd already been divorced once. But the point is that the whole time they were dating, or courting, or whatever you want to call it, Wallis Simpson was married. In fact, the Duke of Windsor had a history of dating married women. The Duke of Windsor and his birthright Let me back up and try to explain briefly how the Duke of Windsor got into that situation. The Duke of Windsor grew up knowing he was destined to be King, but wondering if that's what he wanted, or even if he was qualified. His letters and diaries show that he questioned his right to rule just because of his birth. Being brought up separate from others, with a difficult father who was King, wasn't easy. When he served in World War II, he didn't think it was fair that his fellow soldiers had to endure the trenches and other horrors of war when he wasn't allowed to put himself in any danger. At the same time, he couldn't fathom how French soldiers could follow an officer who was of lower birth rank than they were. He wrestled with a conscious that was developing differently from the way he was raised. After the war, the poor and destitute who couldn't find work in Britain troubled him, but he had few ideas (and in fact, probably little power) to do anything about it. The many married women of the Duke of Windsor Meanwhile, both of the Duke of Windsor's serious relationships were with married women. This wasn't uncommon among the nobles he was surrounded by. At a time when it was difficult for women to hold jobs and make money of their own, marriages were often their &quot;careers.&quot; They were the means to consolidate or preserve wealth. When the nobles in Britain started running out of money, newly wealthy American girls crossed the Atlantic and married for a tiara in exchange for a fortune that helped their husbands hold onto the family estate. Everyone thus having done their duty, no one saw any reason why they shouldn't have a little fun afterward. Courting before the marriage was a business negotiation. Dating after marriage was the romance. The difference was that the Duke always wanted to marry the married woman he was &quot;dating.&quot; He thought it was dishonorable not to. Until Wallis Simpson, neither of the British married women he dated let him get very far with that thought. They understood too well that it would not only jeopardize his position, but threaten the stability of the country. They probably also didn't want to spoil the fun. The history of Wallis Simpson Mrs. Simpson grew up dependent on an uncle to support her and her widowed mother. While no one, including herself, ever called Mrs. Simpson beautiful, she was elegant, intelligent, and had a talent for showing true interest in men. She never lacked for suitors. Sadly, her first husband turned out to be to an abusive alcoholic. She finally got her marriage dissolved on grounds of abandonment. Not long after her first divorce, she married her second husband, Ernest Simpson. He wasn't rich, but he was well off and steady in temperament. The Duke of Windsor meets Wallis Simpson When the Duke was introduced to the Simpsons by friends, the Simpsons were happily married. As a British subject with an American background, Ernest Simpson was thrilled to be in the circle of royalty. It didn't hurt that it helped his business connections. Wallis Simpson thoroughly enjoyed entertaining as part of high society, and the Duke admired a woman who didn't just bow and cater to his every need. He considered that kind of adoration false, and I would guess may be one of the reasons married women were more appealing. They probably weren't as eager to please him as a girl who was trying to catch and marry him. The Duke became devoted to Mrs. Simpson and her lack of fear to give him guidance. Mrs. Simpson became enamored with the lifestyle of luxury and gifts of jewels. She seems to have thought that the Duke's infatuation would run it's course, just like it had with other married women. If she played her cards right she'd have acquired enough gifts for a little security when he moved on, and she and Mr. Simpson would go back to their married life a little more financially secure. Only the Duke was more devoted than usual. He abruptly cut off all ties to his former mistresses, who had been close to him for years, and became fairly isolated. There were some interesting dynamics between the the Duke and Wallis, reported differently depending on who's doing the observing. But by several accounts, and for the rest of his life, the Duke would light up and become more sure of himself whenever Wallis was near. When she was gone, he was dejected and depressed. The Duke of Windsor becomes King But maybe more importantly, the turning point in their relationship may have come when his father died. The Duke of Windsor (as he would come to be known later) was now King Edward VIII of Great Britain. But unlike the summary suggests, he didn't just say, &quot;Oh, oops, well I want to marry an already married woman so I'll just step aside and you can put my brother on the throne.&quot; It was to prove to be a long year for both the British Royalty and Parliament. At first, the Duke seemed to honestly believe that it wouldn't matter to the people whether or not Mrs. Simpson was a divorcee. As the Prince of Wales, he was extremely popular with the public and didn't think anything he did would change their love of him. After all, all of the nobles he was surrounded with fooled around. They even divorced and remarried pretty frequently. The Problem with Wallis Simpson But as Anne Sheba perhaps explained the best in her book, That Woman, that blase view didn't apply to most of the population. One of the reasons that divorces were still difficult to obtain in Britain was that with no careers, women usually had no means of support other than a husband. So it was the women who were against Wallis Simpson divorcing even more than the men. The way they saw it, was if the King married a divorced woman, divorce would become more acceptable, and women would be the ones left destitute. The negotiations to marry Wallis Simpson The Duke argued and negotiated with men in government, and men not in government but still in power (such as Winston Churchill), for months. His brother, the future King George V (father of Elizabeth II) didn't want to be King. The possibility of the Duke marrying Mrs. Simpson, but her not getting a title and their children not becoming heirs, was considered and discarded. You have to remember that all this was going on as Hitler was flaunting the power of Nazi Germany. So in addition to dealing with that, the British government was distracted by their King's romance. It appears that for her part, Mrs. Simpson wanted things to just go on as they were and eventually things would move on one way or the other. She had no real desire to be Queen per say, but she found it impossible to give up the luxury and jewels that her relationship with the Duke gave her. The longer they argued, the more extreme the Duke became. In the end he refused to be crowned unless he could marry Mrs. Simpson before the coronation and have her crowned Queen with him. The longer the argument drug on, the uncertainty started to be a drain on the economy. On top of that, it truly was a constitutional crisis. From this vantage point, with the British monarchy not having any real power, this seems hard to believe. There wren't many kings and queens left after World War I; the British monarchy was a survivor, and barely hanging on. The fall of European Monarchies At the beginning of the 1900's there were monarchies all over Europe. Now, after World War I - still being called the Great War - the global map looked very different. At the time the Duke of Windsor was arguing to marry Wallis Simpson, it was just a few years after most of the royalty of Europe had toppled. Many of them were assassinated. And through Queen Victoria's huge family, many - if not most - of them were related to the British Royal family, such as the last German Kaiser, Wilhelm II. The Duke himself had personally met a number of his European royal relatives who'd met their fate. This included the Russian Tsar, whose entire family was brutally murdered. This happened after the Tsar's cousin - the Duke's father, King George V - refused him asylum in Britain. The toppling of monarchies all over Europe had proven that popular opinion could threaten stability, dissolve a monarchy, and worse. And both the royal family and the government of Britain knew it. The Duke of Windsor Abdicates The argument grew so public that there were threats on Mrs. Simpson's life. She fled to France to stay with friends. In the Duke's defense, part of his decision to not back down was because he believed the woman he was in love with would be ruined, personally and socially, if he deserted her at this point. But he also was personally miserable without her near. He made up his mind abdicate. Still, there were lots of details to be ironed out. What would the Duke now be called? His brother created the new title of Duke of Windsor for him. How would he be paid? Where would he live? A lot of things were discussed, but in the rising panic of the moment, not everything was decided for certain before he left Britain. The Duke and Duchess of Windsor give up the throne to live in &quot;poverty&quot; In due course Mrs. Simpson's divorce became final, the Duke's brother was crowned King, and the Duke and Duchess were married. But a lot of bad feelings remained. The Duke's family was upset that he gave up his responsibilities. King George VI was upset that during his negotiations for his allowance, the Duke had misled him about how much money he had. (&amp;ldquo;A lot&amp;rdquo; in most people's terms. &amp;ldquo;Not enough&amp;rdquo; in his way of thinking. There is also evidence that he had already transferred most of his cash into Mrs. Simpson's name.) It was decided (by someone, it's not clear who) that even though the Duke would still be known as His Royal Highness the Duke of Windsor, his wife would simply be the Duchess of Windsor. Being offended by the refusal of allowing the Duchess to be called officially &amp;ldquo;Her Royal Highness&amp;rdquo; is probably only completely understood by royalty, and perhaps by nobles. But to the Duke, who ironically on one hand didn't think rank by birth was fair, but was raised in the tradition, it was the ultimate insult. So there was tension between the Duke, his family, and the British government. The Duke of Windsor and Hitler Based on his experience in WWI, the Duke thought that getting into any war was the greatest folly. He wasn't alone in thinking that Hitler and Germany should be negotiated with. He thought that Hitler was the only thing standing against the Russian communists and the rest of Europe, and that going against the Fascists would doom the rest of the world to communism. As it turns out, that opinion was right in a lot of ways. When a friend arranged for the Duke to visit Germany and observe what Hitler had done for the poor, working conditions, and housing, he jumped at the chance. If the Duchess couldn't be a Royal Highness, it gave him an opportunity to take her on what amounted to a royal tour, and also to study ways in which the poor could be helped. He naively didn't think it endorsed the atrocities of the Nazis. The Duke and Duchess of Windsor and World War II When war did break out, he was disappointed when Britain joined in, but wanted to serve. A place was finally found for him in France, but there was a lot of confusion when France was invaded. The Duke and Duchess fled but couldn't immediately get off the continent. This is where contradictions and entanglement with Germans really start to complicate things. The Duke and Duchess worried about what would become of their possessions in France. Through German friends, they possibly arranged to make sure their possessions stayed safe. (The Duke had a lot of relatives among the Germans. Queen Victoria's husband, Prince Albert, was German.) The plot by the Nazis to crown the Duke of Windsor King of Great Britain The Germans plotted to kidnap the Duke. They thought that when they invaded England, if they put him on the throne his past popularity would help them. There are a lot of documents to support this. The Duke and Duchess seemed to not know anything about the plot. But they balked at a &quot;suitable position&quot; not being found for the Duke. Then when he was offered the office of Governor of the Bahamas, not only was it still not good enough, but they balked over rumors started by the Germans that the British government itself was out to kill them during or before the trip. The Duke and Duchess of Windsor&amp;nbsp;and the rest of World War II Eventually a friend and adviser &amp;nbsp;convinced them to sail. During the course of the war they continued to harass Winston Churchill and the King about the Duchess' title, their allowance, and money for other matters, which seemed rather selfish given the current world crisis. They took frequent and sometimes overly long trips to the United States and embarrassed the British government by some of their opinions on the war. But maybe it was was a diversion (if not a nice one) for King George VI and Churchill from the even more depressing war. And other than that, the Duke and Duchess worked hard at their new positions. He made some progress with equalizing pay and government reform. She worked for the Red Cross and other relief efforts for the war and the poor. The Duke and Duchess of Windsor after World War II After the war, the Duke still wanted a position. The Royal family and the government still didn't want to raise the rank of the Duchess to Her Royal Highness. The Queen (then Queen Elizabeth, later known as the Queen Mother) feared that the Duke's old popularity would overshadow King George VI, and all their family's sacrifice for him to be King during the war would be discarded. The Duke refused to return to live in Britain if his wife wasn't raised to the same rank as him. On top of that, he still considered himself destitute (even he was a multi-millionaire, by any standard) and if he returned to Britain he would have to pay taxes, the ultimate insult. The Duke and Duchess settled in France, but they spent almost half of every year in the United States. Having discarded their own royalty centuries before (starting with Marie Antoinette's husband), France was now a haven for discarded royalty of other countries. France didn't require the Duke and Duchess to pay taxes, provided personal security, and eventually gave them a mansion in Paris almost rent free. In the minds of the Duke and Duchess, the Duke - as a former King and still royalty - had to live at a certain standard to which he had become accustomed. He didn't even know how to pack his own suitcase, after all. They considered themselves poor and were always afraid of running out of money, but bought luxury items and kept a staff that seemed to be at odds with that. (See The Jewels of the Duchess of Windsor, by John Culme and Nicholas Rayner, to get an idea of what I mean. That really makes their wealth concrete.) The Duke and Duchess of Windsor, a great love story? Some accounts have them as miserable with their lack of royal position, citing letters. Other accounts, some by friends, say they were happy with their life of luxury, travel, entertaining, golf, and gardening. The truth probably lies somewhere in the middle. Their letters were probably mostly written when they were trying to negotiate. Often people complain about things they don't like, but don't take the time to write about things that are going well. If you only read the letters, you might get a skewed perspective. On the other hand, there are friends who you wouldn't tell your complaints to. By all accounts the Duke remained devoted to the Duchess and she, if not devoted, remained loyal to him. Letters to her second husband, though, suggests she never wanted the divorce, she just wanted to have some &quot;fun&quot; for awhile.&amp;nbsp;Perhaps she would have been happiest as mistress of a king. Some stories seemed to indicate that while the Duke always worshiped her, there were times she just barely tolerated him. But she either had the decency, or fear of social downfall, to stick by him once he gave up everything for her. That in itself is admirable. Commitment is what keeps marriages going for the long haul, after all. Maybe the definition of a great romance isn't happily ever after, but the length of the ever after. By that definition, the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson did have a great romance.&amp;nbsp; Who's to blame for the abdication? As I read about the quibbles after the abdication, one of the things that bothered me was the constant refrain of the Duke and Duchess that they hadn't done anything wrong. I won't even go into the list of possibilities and argue the points. But in the last book I read, something struck me that none of the authors pointed out. After his abdication, the Duke gave a speech on the radio. It's famous for the line &quot;... I have found it impossible to carry the heavy burden of responsibility and to discharge my duties as King ... without the support of the woman I love...&quot; But it also contains these lines. &amp;ldquo;There has never been any constitutional difference between me and [the Ministers of the Crown] and between me and Parliament. Bred in the constitutional tradition by my Father, I should never have allowed any such issue to arise.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;(emphasis mine) In the end, the Duke of Windsor abdicated when it became clear that his personal decision was leading to the instability of the government. But unlike his brother, King George VI, he wasn't willing to give up personal happiness for his country. And maybe he couldn't. But at least once, and publicly, he was willing to acknowledge his mistake. UPDATE: Newly unclassified documents show that the government of Great Britain was sorried enough that Wallis Simpson might be a spy and the fascist leaning of the then King Edward VIII that they wire-tapped the King's phone. You can read more about it in the article British Spies Tapped King Edward&amp;rsquo;s Phone to Eavesdrop on Wallis Simpson Calls.&amp;nbsp; The best books about the Duke of Windsor and Wallis Simpson You may have noticed that this isn't a scholarly research paper. I haven't cited any sources, and the professional writer in me feels a little bit guilty about that. Without any footnotes or any authoritative sources (primary sources, meaning I haven&amp;rsquo;t researched original documents myself), you probably shouldn't believe a word you've read here. But here's a list of the books I've read: If you just want to read one book relatively short book, I suggest: That Woman, by Anne Sebba. If you want to bring some of the setting and jewelry vividly to life, to get a sense of the riches of the &quot;impoverished&quot; Duke and Duchess of Windsor add: The Jewels of the Duchess of Windsor&amp;nbsp;By John Clume and Nicholas Rayner. If you want to read a more scholarly work, move on to: King Edward VIII: A Biography by Philip Ziegler For a naturally biased view, and the most difficult read, dig into: A King's Story: The Memoirs of H.R.H. the Duke of Windsor K.G., by the Duke of Windsor (Interesting how he titled his book not &quot;A Duke's Story,&quot; but &quot;A King's Story.&quot; It gives you some insight into how he thought of himself and wanted to be seen.) Also scholarly, and easier to read but an older book, is: The Windsor Story, by J. Bryan III and Charles J.V. Murphy. Finally, for a different point of view read: The Duchess of Windsor, by her friend, Diana Mosley More About Netflix series - The Crown The Crown - Neflix The Crown - Imdb Watching The Crown with Lady Pamela Hicks, Queen Elizabeth's Lady-in-Waiting - India Hicks shares her mother's memories of the true story behind the Netflix series. How Real Is the Crown? Fact-Checking the Series About Queen Elizabeth The Cast of The Crown vs. the Real-Life Royals</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mom Behind the Curtain is up!</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/mom-behind-the-curtain-is-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mom Behind the Curtain is up!" /><published>2015-08-06T14:30:07+00:00</published><updated>2015-08-06T14:30:07+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/mom-behind-the-curtain-is-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/mom-behind-the-curtain-is-up/">&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mombehindthecurtain.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3316&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/wizard-color-800-x-340.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mom behind the curtain&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; /&gt;The Mom Behind the Curtain&lt;/a&gt; ... because every mom wants to be an all-powerful wizard, is now up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1442485477/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1442485477&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=2FTG65GM62VMF6NA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-4055&quot; src=&quot;http://www.mombehindthecurtain.com/curtain/wp-content/uploads/Wizard-of-Oz-350-x-525.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wizard of Oz Collection&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;That's where you'll find all my posts with things related to crafts, children's book lists, and trips. Visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mombehindthecurtain.com/welcome-mom-behind-the-curtain/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Mom Behind the Curtain&lt;/a&gt; and say hello!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">The Mom Behind the Curtain ... because every mom wants to be an all-powerful wizard, is now up! That's where you'll find all my posts with things related to crafts, children's book lists, and trips. Visit&amp;nbsp;The Mom Behind the Curtain and say hello! &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New site - High School, College, Success!</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/new-site-high-school-college-success/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New site - High School, College, Success!" /><published>2015-07-30T20:39:40+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-30T20:39:40+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/new-site-high-school-college-success</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/new-site-high-school-college-success/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-3302 size-full&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/hsclogocolor-399x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;High school college success logo&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;My posts on high school, college and success - challenging the way schools teach success - are now officially moved to my new sight at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.highschoolcollegesuccess.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.highschoolcollegesuccess.com&lt;/a&gt;. Come on over and say hello!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">My posts on high school, college and success - challenging the way schools teach success - are now officially moved to my new sight at www.highschoolcollegesuccess.com. Come on over and say hello!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy Independence Day!</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/independence-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy Independence Day!" /><published>2015-07-03T14:44:34+00:00</published><updated>2015-07-03T14:44:34+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/independence-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/independence-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2212&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/HappyFourth450x271.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HappyFourth450x271&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;271&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start your Independence day off right with some patriotic waffles! Whip cream and berries. Mmmm....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do know how to make fresh whip cream, don't you? It's so easy, and so delicious!&amp;nbsp;So I thought I'd quickly find a link to a recipe on-line of how to make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, the first 5 recipes aren't like I do it. The first three do it with a hand whisk. Um. No.&lt;!--more--&gt; Now, I have seen my mother do it with a fork - but it took a long time! And usually you're in a hurry at breakfast. Yes, use an electric mixer. It's the 21st Century! My family makes ours with granulated sugar and vanilla extract. We use granulated sugar. I think powdered sugar, or confectioners sugar, would give it and off flavor. If you don't use too much granulated sugar and give it only a couple of minutes it will dissolve right in and not be grainy. For the vanilla extract, if you live in Texas or California, Adam's Best Vanilla is the best! No lie. (Note: Even Adams has an extract named Vanilla Extract and that is NOT what you want, you want Adam's Best by Adam's.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's another tip shopping tip about the cream. You'll see cream labelled lost of things: cream, whipping cream, and heavy whipping cream. They will all have different amounts of milk fat and some will whip more than others. You want to read the the labels and find the one with the most milk fat. It will whip the easiest and hold it's peaks the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe I found with the best directions is for unsweetened whipped cream. So at&amp;nbsp;Step 4, when you start to get soft peaks, &amp;nbsp;add a little bit (a tablespoon or so) of sugar and a teaspoon of vanilla. (They tell you to add vanilla at the beginning, but in my experience it seems to be best to add in later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekitchn.com/how-to-make-whipped-cream-cooking-lessons-from-the-kitchn-102056&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Make Whipped Cream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it wasn't even easy to find a video. In fact, in the tutorial that came up first in my google search, I think it was whipped too long and you would start to get that butter flavor. Here's the best video I found. He does a good job of showing you the steps the cream goes through and he adds the sugar late (but he uses powdered sugar.) I also don't put my beater and bowl in the freezer beforehand, rarely whip more than a cup or half cup (it increases in volume as you whip it), and I use a big bowl to contain the splatters. He also goes one step further and gives you a tip for using a pastry bag, but stop before then. (He adds some pudding mix to do that.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/Zbh9rLHGq7E&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">Start your Independence day off right with some patriotic waffles! Whip cream and berries. Mmmm.... You do know how to make fresh whip cream, don't you? It's so easy, and so delicious!&amp;nbsp;So I thought I'd quickly find a link to a recipe on-line of how to make it. To my surprise, the first 5 recipes aren't like I do it. The first three do it with a hand whisk. Um. No. Now, I have seen my mother do it with a fork - but it took a long time! And usually you're in a hurry at breakfast. Yes, use an electric mixer. It's the 21st Century! My family makes ours with granulated sugar and vanilla extract. We use granulated sugar. I think powdered sugar, or confectioners sugar, would give it and off flavor. If you don't use too much granulated sugar and give it only a couple of minutes it will dissolve right in and not be grainy. For the vanilla extract, if you live in Texas or California, Adam's Best Vanilla is the best! No lie. (Note: Even Adams has an extract named Vanilla Extract and that is NOT what you want, you want Adam's Best by Adam's.) Here's another tip shopping tip about the cream. You'll see cream labelled lost of things: cream, whipping cream, and heavy whipping cream. They will all have different amounts of milk fat and some will whip more than others. You want to read the the labels and find the one with the most milk fat. It will whip the easiest and hold it's peaks the best. The recipe I found with the best directions is for unsweetened whipped cream. So at&amp;nbsp;Step 4, when you start to get soft peaks, &amp;nbsp;add a little bit (a tablespoon or so) of sugar and a teaspoon of vanilla. (They tell you to add vanilla at the beginning, but in my experience it seems to be best to add in later.) How to Make Whipped Cream And it wasn't even easy to find a video. In fact, in the tutorial that came up first in my google search, I think it was whipped too long and you would start to get that butter flavor. Here's the best video I found. He does a good job of showing you the steps the cream goes through and he adds the sugar late (but he uses powdered sugar.) I also don't put my beater and bowl in the freezer beforehand, rarely whip more than a cup or half cup (it increases in volume as you whip it), and I use a big bowl to contain the splatters. He also goes one step further and gives you a tip for using a pastry bag, but stop before then. (He adds some pudding mix to do that.) https://youtu.be/Zbh9rLHGq7E &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Changes are Coming! - with WordPress tutorials for beginners</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/the-changes-are-coming-with-wordpress-tutorials-for-beginners/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Changes are Coming! - with WordPress tutorials for beginners" /><published>2015-06-10T17:00:44+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-10T17:00:44+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/the-changes-are-coming-with-wordpress-tutorials-for-beginners</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/the-changes-are-coming-with-wordpress-tutorials-for-beginners/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/wordpress-tutorial-esivy-logo-300-x-150.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-1626&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/wordpress-tutorial-esivy-logo-300-x-150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blogging basics - Wordpress tutorial, Wordpress Security Tips&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I posted a month or so ago that I had a new URL and the website would be moving, but when you do your own development, things can take awhile. It can take even longer if you're trying to do thing &quot;right.&quot;&amp;nbsp;For example, Austin has a very active WordPress community,&amp;nbsp;so earlier this week I attended a WordPress MeetUp about web site security. And I wrote a post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost-security-tips/&quot;&gt;Wordpress Security Tips for Beginners.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this process, you might notice some things on this blog preparing for the move. If you don't see it already, soon I'll be using the template Foodie Pro with Genesis on this site, just so I can check out how it's going to work. But it won't be completely styled, so a few things might look out of place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside to how thoroughly I'm researching everything, if you happened to design your own website, or want to, I'm working on a pretty extensive series of WordPress tutorials for beginners to the more advanced, on everything from buying your domain, setting up local test sites on your own computer, migrating a designed site to another location and styling Foodie Pro for Genesis into a Lifestyle blog. So be sure to keep up with the changes or sign up to follow my blog in email!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff00ff;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog Signup&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;- get all posts in email&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!-- Begin MailChimp Signup Form --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;form id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; class=&quot;validate&quot; action=&quot;http://esivy.us5.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=d18cc3d317104ea21fdd75010&amp;amp;id=89dfe83bae&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; name=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mc-field-group&quot;&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot;&gt;Email Address &lt;/label&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input id=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot; class=&quot;required email&quot; name=&quot;EMAIL&quot; type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mce-responses&quot; class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;input id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; name=&quot;subscribe&quot; type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Subscribe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">I posted a month or so ago that I had a new URL and the website would be moving, but when you do your own development, things can take awhile. It can take even longer if you're trying to do thing &quot;right.&quot;&amp;nbsp;For example, Austin has a very active WordPress community,&amp;nbsp;so earlier this week I attended a WordPress MeetUp about web site security. And I wrote a post, Wordpress Security Tips for Beginners. During this process, you might notice some things on this blog preparing for the move. If you don't see it already, soon I'll be using the template Foodie Pro with Genesis on this site, just so I can check out how it's going to work. But it won't be completely styled, so a few things might look out of place. The upside to how thoroughly I'm researching everything, if you happened to design your own website, or want to, I'm working on a pretty extensive series of WordPress tutorials for beginners to the more advanced, on everything from buying your domain, setting up local test sites on your own computer, migrating a designed site to another location and styling Foodie Pro for Genesis into a Lifestyle blog. So be sure to keep up with the changes or sign up to follow my blog in email! Blog Signup&amp;nbsp;- get all posts in email Email Address</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wordpress Security Tips for the Beginner</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/wordpress-security-tips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wordpress Security Tips for the Beginner" /><published>2015-06-09T18:25:20+00:00</published><updated>2015-06-09T18:25:20+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/wordpress-security-tips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/wordpress-security-tips/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-full wp-image-1626&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/wordpress-tutorial-esivy-logo-300-x-150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blogging basics - Wordpress tutorial, Wordpress Security Tips&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;Yesterday I attended a WordPress Meetup about basic security presented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://pleiadesservices.com/about-us/nicholas-r-batik/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nick Batik.&lt;/a&gt; WordPress Meetups are awesome free gatherings where developers volunteer to teach others all about WordPress and I've been to quite a few. I'm working on a whole series about making a WordPress site (my &lt;a href=&quot;/install-favicon-wordpress/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Install a Favicon on Wordpress tutorial&lt;/a&gt; will also be part of that series), but this security information is too important to keep to myself until I get this site moved and the series completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your site gets hacked, to add to all the other headaches&amp;nbsp;you can get blacklisted by Google. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://sucuri.net/website-security/google-blacklisted-my-website&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Understand Google Website Blacklists&lt;/a&gt;) You can see Nick's slides from the presentation on the WPAustin blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wpaustin.com/2015/06/revisiting-wordpress-security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Revisting WordPress Security.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; There are links to lots of authoritative sites to learn more information. (Note: Currently, the slide program only works in Firefox for me, I can only see the first slide when I use Chrome.)&amp;nbsp;When you're searching around the web, it's really helpful to learn where the sites are that you can really trust. That's one of the things I love about going to these WordPress meetups. But below are are some basic WordPress security tips, practices that even a&amp;nbsp;beginner can easily tackle, that were my take-away from the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're taking money on your site -- for example, setting up an ecommerce site or the like -- then it would be a good idea to pay for a monthly security plan from someone like &lt;a href=&quot;https://sucuri.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sucuri&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as well, and/or use a paid security plugin like the pro versions of the security plugins I cover below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;WordPress Security Tips for the Beginner&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Choose difficult passwords for your WordPress admin and other users, and change them regularly.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Blog as an editor, not as an administrator of your site.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you login to Wordpress anywhere someone could be &quot;watching,&quot; it's best to usually login as someone other than the administrator. Most people have probably heard that random &quot;free wifi&quot; that's publicly accessible may have been set up by a hacker. But places vulnerable to hackers include public wifi like at a coffee house or even your own wifi if you live or work somewhere that others can &quot;see&quot; that you have wifi available. Every time you login as admin in a vulnerable location is an opportunity for someone to scrape your password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Maintain your site, or hire someone to maintain it for you.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, after you set up your site, it's not going to stay done. This is the most frustrating part of software for me. (I hate it when my phone updates to such an extent that it's like learning a new phone all over again. Sometimes I long for the days when all twelve buttons stayed in one place, on every phone, and you could always find your phone because it was attached to the wall. And then I take a picture outside with my smart phone and instantly send it to someone with a few clicks, and wonder how I lived without it!) In a perfect world, we wouldn't have to update our software as much. If all the software engineers were really smart, then old versions would always work with the new, but that's not always true. And unfortunately there are people out there just looking for ways to hack any software that's out there. So when holes are found, they continually need to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When software is improved or security issues are discovered, new versions of WordPress and plugins will be released and someone will have to update them on your site. This is called maintenance of your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you set up your site, then the maintenance person is you. If you hired someone to make your site, check and see if you can hire them for maintenance. If you don't have maintenance agreement with them, you'll either need to do it yourself or hire someone else to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Is it just me that needed to have this spelled out, or is it too basic? I know that early on I saw something about maintenance of websites, and admit it just kind of slipped right past me. I wasn't too concerned with keeping my site updated with the latest bells and whistles. And somehow I didn't think there would be many security updates.&amp;nbsp;I think mostly because I always like to think the best of people and that hackers aren't as prevalent as they are. But when I moved from wordpress.com to wordpress.org and would be paying for my own hosting, I recognized that I would have to become more pay more attention about security.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Install the latest version of WordPress and keep it updated.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic, I know. But it doesn't hurt to be reminded. If you usually write posts on your site as &quot;editor&quot; or another user, don't forget to login as administrator on a regular schedule and check for updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Update Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins are even more likely to have security cracks that the main WordPress install. Be sure to update them. If you installed your plugin&amp;nbsp;from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress Plugins Directory&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(which you can access from Dashboard &gt; Plugins &gt; Add New &gt; &lt;em&gt;type on the &quot;Search Plugins&quot; box&lt;/em&gt;) then WordPress will keep the admin user up to date on available updates. However, if you purchase any premium plugins, you may need to check for updates back at the developer's site! For beginners, it seems like a really good idea to just stick to things you find available through WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I'm sure you've heard it before, but if you deactivate a plugin, then delete it. Otherwise the code is still sitting on your site, waiting to be exploited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. Backup your Site on a Regular Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/updraftplus/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Updraft Plus Backup and Restoration Plugin,&lt;/a&gt; available through your WordPress Plugin dashboard. There are also some good paid options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. Install a basic security plugin.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free plugins, available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WordPress Plugins Directory&lt;/a&gt; include&lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/sucuri-scanner/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;Sucuri Security - Auditing, Malware Scanner and Hardening&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/better-wp-security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iThemes Security&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/wordfence/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wordfence Security.&lt;/a&gt; They all have paid pro-versions available if you need more security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;8. If you want to use free themes or plugins, only use ones approved by WordPress and available to you through your WordPress dashboard.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a ton of free stuff out there, and most of it is by good, honest software writers who just want to share their work. Anyone can write a plugin or a free theme, so quality varies. If you know code and can check it, then it's a great resource. But it's easy for hackers to install malware or vulnerabilities in free themes and plugins, so if you don't know code it's best to stick with themes and plugins approved by WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;9. If you buy themes or plugins, stick to well-known names.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well known developers include StudioPress - they make Genesis which I'm working on installing - and ithemes. Again, don't forget to check on updates regularly if they aren't available from your WordPress dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10. If you're not an a monthly security plan, manually scan your site for malware at a trusted site like&amp;nbsp;https://sitecheck.sucuri.net/ on a regular schedule.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Optional Tip: use .htaccess to protect your Wordpress site.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, this is an advanced technique that you really need to be experience with code to do, so it's probably only a method for beginning WordPress users who already know how to code. I'm not sure why it was mentioned as a beginner best practice, but probably if you know what you're doing, it's a really good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;11. Change the WordPress default database prefix when you install WordPress.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this was not something that made it onto the developer's list; it was something I ran across in my searches and asked about. It's so basic that the developer didn't think to include it in his presentation. That's part of the disconnect between developers and people new to WordPress or coding; there are things that are just so basic to a developer that they don't think anyone needs to be told again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about why you would want to change your database prefix, what a database prefix is, and how a hacker would exploit it at the post&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpwhitesecurity.com/wordpress-security/change-wordpress-database-prefix/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Is WordPress More Secure with a Changed Database Prefix?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the roadblock I ran into in my research - the best time to do this is during your install. But it's so basic to the install, that all the developers writing about this assume that you know how to do it, and all they're writing about is how to change the prefix on a site that's already running, like in the post&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wpbeginner.com/wp-tutorials/how-to-change-the-wordpress-database-prefix-to-improve-security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Change the WordPress Database Prefix to Improve Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first asked about this at the MeetUp, Nick very patiently explained where to find the box to do this on my install, after I entered my admin name and password. Yeah. Sounds pretty basic, I know. But here's the thing. As we discussed it more and we looked around a little on the web, we discovered that if you use the one-button WordPress install available on your host, the option might not be there! So when I did my one button install this last time for a test site, I probably didn't see a place to change the WordPress database prefix. Developers who teach courses like this aren't using the one-button install, so they don't know the option has disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the recesses of my memory, I seem to remember that this option might have been there when I did my first WordPress install a year or two ago, and I think my techie teenager instructed me to change it. So, I'm off to hunt&amp;nbsp;around for a way to install WordPress that this option still exists! And hopefully, I'll get done with all this research soon and manage to get up my new sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;UPDATE 12. MAKE SURE YOUR MEMBERSHIP REGISTRATION IS TURNED OFF&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I just learned from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bishless.com/category/wordpress/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Daniel Bishop&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00IEM7BYO/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00IEM7BYO&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=ID2Z7PW5HPKG3CSH&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Everything But the Posts'&lt;/a&gt; Facebook group : after your WordPress install, on your Dashboard &gt; Settings &gt; Membership - make sure &quot;Anyone can register&quot; is NOT checked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* How do you know if you've been hacked? Signs to look for that you've been hacked include a new user showing up in your dashboard that you didn't add, and SPAM ads appearing on your site. For more information and steps to take if you have been hacked, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sucuri.net/2015/06/your-website-hacked-but-no-signs-of-infection.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Your Website Hacked but No Signs of Infection.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** For more information on WordPress Security tips, slides for this WordPress Meetup will be posted on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wpaustin.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wpaustin.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">Yesterday I attended a WordPress Meetup about basic security presented by Nick Batik. WordPress Meetups are awesome free gatherings where developers volunteer to teach others all about WordPress and I've been to quite a few. I'm working on a whole series about making a WordPress site (my How to Install a Favicon on Wordpress tutorial will also be part of that series), but this security information is too important to keep to myself until I get this site moved and the series completed. If your site gets hacked, to add to all the other headaches&amp;nbsp;you can get blacklisted by Google. (Understand Google Website Blacklists) You can see Nick's slides from the presentation on the WPAustin blog, Revisting WordPress Security.&amp;nbsp; There are links to lots of authoritative sites to learn more information. (Note: Currently, the slide program only works in Firefox for me, I can only see the first slide when I use Chrome.)&amp;nbsp;When you're searching around the web, it's really helpful to learn where the sites are that you can really trust. That's one of the things I love about going to these WordPress meetups. But below are are some basic WordPress security tips, practices that even a&amp;nbsp;beginner can easily tackle, that were my take-away from the discussion. &amp;nbsp; If you're taking money on your site -- for example, setting up an ecommerce site or the like -- then it would be a good idea to pay for a monthly security plan from someone like Sucuri&amp;nbsp;as well, and/or use a paid security plugin like the pro versions of the security plugins I cover below. WordPress Security Tips for the Beginner 1. Choose difficult passwords for your WordPress admin and other users, and change them regularly. 2. Blog as an editor, not as an administrator of your site. If you login to Wordpress anywhere someone could be &quot;watching,&quot; it's best to usually login as someone other than the administrator. Most people have probably heard that random &quot;free wifi&quot; that's publicly accessible may have been set up by a hacker. But places vulnerable to hackers include public wifi like at a coffee house or even your own wifi if you live or work somewhere that others can &quot;see&quot; that you have wifi available. Every time you login as admin in a vulnerable location is an opportunity for someone to scrape your password. 3. Maintain your site, or hire someone to maintain it for you. Unfortunately, after you set up your site, it's not going to stay done. This is the most frustrating part of software for me. (I hate it when my phone updates to such an extent that it's like learning a new phone all over again. Sometimes I long for the days when all twelve buttons stayed in one place, on every phone, and you could always find your phone because it was attached to the wall. And then I take a picture outside with my smart phone and instantly send it to someone with a few clicks, and wonder how I lived without it!) In a perfect world, we wouldn't have to update our software as much. If all the software engineers were really smart, then old versions would always work with the new, but that's not always true. And unfortunately there are people out there just looking for ways to hack any software that's out there. So when holes are found, they continually need to be fixed. When software is improved or security issues are discovered, new versions of WordPress and plugins will be released and someone will have to update them on your site. This is called maintenance of your site. If you set up your site, then the maintenance person is you. If you hired someone to make your site, check and see if you can hire them for maintenance. If you don't have maintenance agreement with them, you'll either need to do it yourself or hire someone else to do it. (Is it just me that needed to have this spelled out, or is it too basic? I know that early on I saw something about maintenance of websites, and admit it just kind of slipped right past me. I wasn't too concerned with keeping my site updated with the latest bells and whistles. And somehow I didn't think there would be many security updates.&amp;nbsp;I think mostly because I always like to think the best of people and that hackers aren't as prevalent as they are. But when I moved from wordpress.com to wordpress.org and would be paying for my own hosting, I recognized that I would have to become more pay more attention about security.) 4. Install the latest version of WordPress and keep it updated. Basic, I know. But it doesn't hurt to be reminded. If you usually write posts on your site as &quot;editor&quot; or another user, don't forget to login as administrator on a regular schedule and check for updates. 5. Update Plugins Plugins are even more likely to have security cracks that the main WordPress install. Be sure to update them. If you installed your plugin&amp;nbsp;from the WordPress Plugins Directory&amp;nbsp;(which you can access from Dashboard &gt; Plugins &gt; Add New &gt; type on the &quot;Search Plugins&quot; box) then WordPress will keep the admin user up to date on available updates. However, if you purchase any premium plugins, you may need to check for updates back at the developer's site! For beginners, it seems like a really good idea to just stick to things you find available through WordPress. And I'm sure you've heard it before, but if you deactivate a plugin, then delete it. Otherwise the code is still sitting on your site, waiting to be exploited. 6. Backup your Site on a Regular Schedule I use Updraft Plus Backup and Restoration Plugin, available through your WordPress Plugin dashboard. There are also some good paid options. 7. Install a basic security plugin. Free plugins, available from the WordPress Plugins Directory include&amp;nbsp;Sucuri Security - Auditing, Malware Scanner and Hardening,&amp;nbsp;iThemes Security, and Wordfence Security. They all have paid pro-versions available if you need more security. 8. If you want to use free themes or plugins, only use ones approved by WordPress and available to you through your WordPress dashboard. There's a ton of free stuff out there, and most of it is by good, honest software writers who just want to share their work. Anyone can write a plugin or a free theme, so quality varies. If you know code and can check it, then it's a great resource. But it's easy for hackers to install malware or vulnerabilities in free themes and plugins, so if you don't know code it's best to stick with themes and plugins approved by WordPress. 9. If you buy themes or plugins, stick to well-known names. Well known developers include StudioPress - they make Genesis which I'm working on installing - and ithemes. Again, don't forget to check on updates regularly if they aren't available from your WordPress dashboard. 10. If you're not an a monthly security plan, manually scan your site for malware at a trusted site like&amp;nbsp;https://sitecheck.sucuri.net/ on a regular schedule. It's free. Optional Tip: use .htaccess to protect your Wordpress site. Actually, this is an advanced technique that you really need to be experience with code to do, so it's probably only a method for beginning WordPress users who already know how to code. I'm not sure why it was mentioned as a beginner best practice, but probably if you know what you're doing, it's a really good idea. 11. Change the WordPress default database prefix when you install WordPress. Now, this was not something that made it onto the developer's list; it was something I ran across in my searches and asked about. It's so basic that the developer didn't think to include it in his presentation. That's part of the disconnect between developers and people new to WordPress or coding; there are things that are just so basic to a developer that they don't think anyone needs to be told again. You can read more about why you would want to change your database prefix, what a database prefix is, and how a hacker would exploit it at the post&amp;nbsp;Is WordPress More Secure with a Changed Database Prefix? Here's the roadblock I ran into in my research - the best time to do this is during your install. But it's so basic to the install, that all the developers writing about this assume that you know how to do it, and all they're writing about is how to change the prefix on a site that's already running, like in the post&amp;nbsp;How to Change the WordPress Database Prefix to Improve Security. When I first asked about this at the MeetUp, Nick very patiently explained where to find the box to do this on my install, after I entered my admin name and password. Yeah. Sounds pretty basic, I know. But here's the thing. As we discussed it more and we looked around a little on the web, we discovered that if you use the one-button WordPress install available on your host, the option might not be there! So when I did my one button install this last time for a test site, I probably didn't see a place to change the WordPress database prefix. Developers who teach courses like this aren't using the one-button install, so they don't know the option has disappeared. Somewhere in the recesses of my memory, I seem to remember that this option might have been there when I did my first WordPress install a year or two ago, and I think my techie teenager instructed me to change it. So, I'm off to hunt&amp;nbsp;around for a way to install WordPress that this option still exists! And hopefully, I'll get done with all this research soon and manage to get up my new sites. UPDATE 12. MAKE SURE YOUR MEMBERSHIP REGISTRATION IS TURNED OFF Another thing I just learned from Daniel Bishop in the Everything But the Posts' Facebook group : after your WordPress install, on your Dashboard &gt; Settings &gt; Membership - make sure &quot;Anyone can register&quot; is NOT checked. * How do you know if you've been hacked? Signs to look for that you've been hacked include a new user showing up in your dashboard that you didn't add, and SPAM ads appearing on your site. For more information and steps to take if you have been hacked, check out Your Website Hacked but No Signs of Infection.&amp;nbsp; ** For more information on WordPress Security tips, slides for this WordPress Meetup will be posted on&amp;nbsp;wpaustin.com.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dont miss Tomorrowland! A parents review</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/tomorrowland-a-parents-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't miss Tomorrowland! A parent's review" /><published>2015-05-26T21:05:25+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-26T21:05:25+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/tomorrowland-a-parents-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/tomorrowland-a-parents-review/">&lt;p&gt;Our family was able to catch Tomorrowland during it&amp;rsquo;s premier holiday weekend, and we&amp;rsquo;re glad we did! Because&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They showed the trailer for Star Wars the Force Awakens!&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://youtu.be/ngElkyQ6Rhs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I kid. That definitely was&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the best part of seeing Tomorrowland.&amp;nbsp;But I did grow up during the golden age of the original Star Wars movies. Or should I admit, the golden age of Luke Skywalker and Han Solo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Solo and Chewbacca flash past in the last scene of the trailer. While wookies don&amp;rsquo;t seem to gray as they age, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help thinking. &amp;ldquo;Wow, Han Solo&amp;rsquo;s old.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then Tomorrowland started up and the first person you see is &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3187&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Tomorrowland-Clooney.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tomorrowland Clooney&quot; width=&quot;648&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow, George Clooney&amp;rsquo;s getting old.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm&amp;hellip; I must be getting old. Nah. Besides, if I am, these two make it look pretty good. When I mentioned the men getting old, my daughter protested &amp;ldquo;But George Clooney looks good old!&amp;rdquo; (Sorry, Harrison. My son is a true Jedi, but my girls are clueless when it comes to Star Wars. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to try to fix that with a marathon this summer&amp;mdash; if randomly glimpsing the Darth Vader-making volcano scene hasn&amp;rsquo;t spoiled them for good. I do hope that under Disney Star Wars follows the lead of Tomorrowland in getting back to more family-friendly films.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, yes, Tomorrowland! That&amp;rsquo;s what we were talking about, right? What did our family think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Disney.com/Tomorrowland&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tomorrowland&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3188&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Tomorrowland-city.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tomorrowland futuristic city&quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thought it was a really great time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie does a great job of accomplishing the odd mix of evoking nostalgia and excitement of the future at the same time, just like Disney World&amp;rsquo;s Tomorrowland in Magic Kingdom and Epcot. In fact, the movie might just be one big giant advertisement because I found myself wanting&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;/trip-planning-tips-for-disney-parks/&quot;&gt;to plan a trip there&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, back to the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I love Tomorrowland for is all the cool scenery and futuristic gadgets . It&amp;rsquo;s just fun. And I love a fun movie. (If you&amp;rsquo;re curious if we&amp;rsquo;ll really get any of &amp;nbsp;the cool technology of Tomorrowland any time soon, check out the post &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livescience.com/50937-tomorrowland-movie-future-tech.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jetpacks! Robots! 'Tomorrowland's' Awesome Vision of the Future&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acting is fantastic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all agreed that our favorite parts included the wheat field. Both from the fantastical view, and how funny it is when Casey keeps running into things when she thinks she's in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I really like is the central message of the movie. Yes, I said message. And they kind of hit you over the head with it, but in a good way. I&amp;rsquo;ll go into that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Because some parents may be wondering, should I take young children to see Tomorrowland?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind we are now (officially!) a family of teens and we saw this just two days after the &lt;a href=&quot;http://marvel.com/movies/movie/193/avengers_age_of_ultron&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Avengers: Age of Ultron&lt;/a&gt;. That said, Tomorrowland is pretty tame. The writers made a real attempt to keep everything &amp;ldquo;safe and responsible.&amp;rdquo; For example, one of main characters, Casey, does go off on her own, but after a day she calls her dad and leaves a message to apologize and let him know she&amp;rsquo;s okay. It's tame enough that my youngest thought the ending solution might have been too &quot;easy.&quot; The violence is pretty much of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003CSX6HQ/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B003CSX6HQ&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=J2Z3VHIC7F4KSBTA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Home Alone&lt;/a&gt; slapstick type. Aside from a bloody nose, the major injuries occur to robots. But there is one rather major type of injury &amp;mdash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;&gt;SPOILER ALERT FOR TOMORROWLAND&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a death of a main character in the movie, a robot who looks like a young girl. You are well aware she&amp;rsquo;s animatronic at that point, and you get the idea that she&amp;rsquo;s lived a long time. However, it might be upsetting to young kids who are genuinely fond of stuffed animals and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I just heard from my daughter who saw Tomorrowland again today with a group of middle schoolers. (It was a &quot;rain plan&quot; reward field trip for science fair participation.) Tomorrowland is plenty intense for tween/teen girls who are sensitive! They were scared, but not permanently scarred. It was just tense enough to be thrilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;&gt;END SPOILER ALERT For Tomorrowland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #3366ff;&quot;&gt;Begin Minor Plot Give-Away For Tomorrowland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the message of the movie, that I think bears repeating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a time when watching the world news will make everything seem hopeless&amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For that matter, in a time when just &lt;a href=&quot;/why-is-required-school-reading-so-depressing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;your child&amp;rsquo;s required reading list for English&lt;/a&gt; will make you feel hopeless&amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In a time when we not only seem to dread and dwell on tragedy, but embrace it in the form of a love for dystopian novels and movies &amp;mdash;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about the importance of Dreamers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about the importance of Dreamers Doing something.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about Dreamers Doing something to Save the World.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you&amp;rsquo;ve got a little dreamer you&amp;rsquo;d like to inspire, check out these directions for Disney Jet Pack Balloon Races! Because a big part of &lt;a href=&quot;/success-factors-whats-the-best-way-to-guide-your-child-through-high-school-to-be-a-success-in-college-and-in-life/&quot;&gt;setting your kids up for success&lt;/a&gt; is inspiring them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/tomorrowland_pdf_555d2b6615a90.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3193&quot; src=&quot;/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/tomorrowland-balloon-race.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tomorrowland activity jet pack balloon races&quot; width=&quot;234&quot; height=&quot;181&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: At the two movie theaters our family goes to, Disney had the only non-rated R movies showing. (Tomorrowland PG and Avengers: Age of Ultron PG13.) Thank you Disney! If you like having family friendly options at the movie theaters, get out there and support the PG-rated movies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was not compensated in any way for this posts; we paid for our own movie tickets. Thoughts about Tomorrowland are my own. Media from Walt Disney Studios and Youtube.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">Our family was able to catch Tomorrowland during it&amp;rsquo;s premier holiday weekend, and we&amp;rsquo;re glad we did! Because&amp;hellip; They showed the trailer for Star Wars the Force Awakens! https://youtu.be/ngElkyQ6Rhs No, I kid. That definitely was&amp;nbsp;not the best part of seeing Tomorrowland.&amp;nbsp;But I did grow up during the golden age of the original Star Wars movies. Or should I admit, the golden age of Luke Skywalker and Han Solo. Han Solo and Chewbacca flash past in the last scene of the trailer. While wookies don&amp;rsquo;t seem to gray as they age, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help thinking. &amp;ldquo;Wow, Han Solo&amp;rsquo;s old.&amp;rdquo; And then Tomorrowland started up and the first person you see is &amp;mdash; &amp;ldquo;Wow, George Clooney&amp;rsquo;s getting old.&amp;rdquo; Hmm&amp;hellip; I must be getting old. Nah. Besides, if I am, these two make it look pretty good. When I mentioned the men getting old, my daughter protested &amp;ldquo;But George Clooney looks good old!&amp;rdquo; (Sorry, Harrison. My son is a true Jedi, but my girls are clueless when it comes to Star Wars. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to try to fix that with a marathon this summer&amp;mdash; if randomly glimpsing the Darth Vader-making volcano scene hasn&amp;rsquo;t spoiled them for good. I do hope that under Disney Star Wars follows the lead of Tomorrowland in getting back to more family-friendly films.) Oh, yes, Tomorrowland! That&amp;rsquo;s what we were talking about, right? What did our family think of Tomorrowland? We thought it was a really great time! The movie does a great job of accomplishing the odd mix of evoking nostalgia and excitement of the future at the same time, just like Disney World&amp;rsquo;s Tomorrowland in Magic Kingdom and Epcot. In fact, the movie might just be one big giant advertisement because I found myself wanting&amp;nbsp;to plan a trip there&amp;hellip; Oh yes, back to the movie. The first thing I love Tomorrowland for is all the cool scenery and futuristic gadgets . It&amp;rsquo;s just fun. And I love a fun movie. (If you&amp;rsquo;re curious if we&amp;rsquo;ll really get any of &amp;nbsp;the cool technology of Tomorrowland any time soon, check out the post Jetpacks! Robots! 'Tomorrowland's' Awesome Vision of the Future.) The acting is fantastic! We all agreed that our favorite parts included the wheat field. Both from the fantastical view, and how funny it is when Casey keeps running into things when she thinks she's in the field. But what I really like is the central message of the movie. Yes, I said message. And they kind of hit you over the head with it, but in a good way. I&amp;rsquo;ll go into that later. Because some parents may be wondering, should I take young children to see Tomorrowland? Keep in mind we are now (officially!) a family of teens and we saw this just two days after the Avengers: Age of Ultron. That said, Tomorrowland is pretty tame. The writers made a real attempt to keep everything &amp;ldquo;safe and responsible.&amp;rdquo; For example, one of main characters, Casey, does go off on her own, but after a day she calls her dad and leaves a message to apologize and let him know she&amp;rsquo;s okay. It's tame enough that my youngest thought the ending solution might have been too &quot;easy.&quot; The violence is pretty much of the Home Alone slapstick type. Aside from a bloody nose, the major injuries occur to robots. But there is one rather major type of injury &amp;mdash; SPOILER ALERT FOR TOMORROWLAND There is a death of a main character in the movie, a robot who looks like a young girl. You are well aware she&amp;rsquo;s animatronic at that point, and you get the idea that she&amp;rsquo;s lived a long time. However, it might be upsetting to young kids who are genuinely fond of stuffed animals and the like. UPDATE: I just heard from my daughter who saw Tomorrowland again today with a group of middle schoolers. (It was a &quot;rain plan&quot; reward field trip for science fair participation.) Tomorrowland is plenty intense for tween/teen girls who are sensitive! They were scared, but not permanently scarred. It was just tense enough to be thrilling. END SPOILER ALERT For Tomorrowland Begin Minor Plot Give-Away For Tomorrowland Here&amp;rsquo;s the message of the movie, that I think bears repeating. In a time when watching the world news will make everything seem hopeless&amp;mdash; For that matter, in a time when just your child&amp;rsquo;s required reading list for English will make you feel hopeless&amp;mdash; In a time when we not only seem to dread and dwell on tragedy, but embrace it in the form of a love for dystopian novels and movies &amp;mdash; It&amp;rsquo;s about the importance of Dreamers. It&amp;rsquo;s about the importance of Dreamers Doing something. It&amp;rsquo;s about Dreamers Doing something to Save the World. And if you&amp;rsquo;ve got a little dreamer you&amp;rsquo;d like to inspire, check out these directions for Disney Jet Pack Balloon Races! Because a big part of setting your kids up for success is inspiring them. Note: At the two movie theaters our family goes to, Disney had the only non-rated R movies showing. (Tomorrowland PG and Avengers: Age of Ultron PG13.) Thank you Disney! If you like having family friendly options at the movie theaters, get out there and support the PG-rated movies! I was not compensated in any way for this posts; we paid for our own movie tickets. Thoughts about Tomorrowland are my own. Media from Walt Disney Studios and Youtube.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Picking a domain name for a lifestyle blog or mommy blog</title><link href="https://esivy.github.io/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Picking a domain name for a lifestyle blog or mommy blog" /><published>2015-05-14T19:25:06+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-14T19:25:06+00:00</updated><id>https://esivy.github.io/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://esivy.github.io/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog/">&lt;p&gt;It can be tricky to pick a domain name for a lifestyle blog. I like the terms &quot;lifestyle blog&quot; or &quot;mommy blog&quot; because the topics can be so broad on them, which is what has turned out to happen here in my little corner of the internet. But in some ways, that seems to make coming up with a domain name and buying a URL&amp;nbsp;more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before I get into all that, maybe your wondering - Exactly what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a domain name? And if you look on the internet (like I did), it will become clear to you that all of the definitions were written by software engineers who knew&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what they were talking about. But after you read their three paragraph definition &lt;em&gt;you'll&lt;/em&gt; have no clue what they're talking about.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a simple way to define domain name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at that string of letters in your browser bar. That's this webpage's URL. (On this webpage right now you should see http://localhost/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog.&amp;nbsp;It will change after I switch over to my new domain name.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple way to define URL is the address of a webpage on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;domain name&lt;/em&gt; is part of the webpage's URL; it's the &quot;title&quot; or &quot;name&quot; that comes immediately after either &quot;http://&quot; or &quot;www.&quot;, before the next dot back-slash (/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this post, the domain name for this website is &lt;strong&gt;esivy.com.&lt;/strong&gt; You can see it in the URL for this webpage in your browser bar at the top of this page which I've copied below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://&lt;strong&gt;esivy.com&lt;/strong&gt;/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to the homepage of a web&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=XAFBZVRW6ULJQODX&quot;&gt;Amazon homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=esiv-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, you'll see only the domain name in the browser bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go to another page on the website, like this one for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/098623530X/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=098623530X&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=PTTNMEUFRAIGFVGG&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Miri Attwater and the Oceans' Secret&lt;/a&gt;, after the&amp;nbsp;domain name you'll see bunch of other letters or numbers to give the address for that specific web&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;page&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;on the web&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;site&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Amazon.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now back to choosing a domain name for a lifestyle blog. Why come up with a clever domain name for the URL of a blog? It seems like the title bar on this webpage has had &quot;creative tagline in the works for here&quot; for ages.&amp;nbsp;I've done lots of thinking and brainstorming trying to come up with a blog name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've read on the internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amylynnandrews.com/how-to-choose-a-domain-name/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to choose a domain name by Amy Lynn Andrews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.problogger.net/archives/2015/05/13/4-things-to-consider-when-choosing-your-domain-name/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;4 Things to Consider When Choosing Your Domain Name by ProBlogger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I've read books:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0615919294/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0615919294&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=TSNOU6XJIFKMCIXI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Everything&amp;nbsp;But the Posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0692236511/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0692236511&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=esiv-20&amp;amp;linkId=C3V5MI35PIOGNZHK&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;How to Blog for Profit: Without Selling Your Soul&lt;/a&gt; (disclaimer, I am a&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; way from that profit part)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked for inspiration from parenting, mommy and lifestyle blog s with names I like. (Surprisingly, if you search for &quot;top mommy blogs&quot; or &quot;best lifestyle blogs&quot; you'll come up with nothing that's useful. Nada. Zilch. So I'll include a list of the best lifestyle blogs with names I like at the end of this post.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the perfect domain name was elusive. A few months ago, I gave up. I took comfort in the fact that lots of blogs were starting to just use the names of their author. But, I did notice that while I've learned some bloggers' names, I'm more likely to remember a clever blog URL the first time I encounter it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to be making the switch soon to the Genesis platform, and while I was researching it I came across the new lifestyle blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mycrazyeverafter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MyCrazyEverAfter.com&lt;/a&gt;. So clever. So easy to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was once again inspired to brainstorm. And then, while I did my after-school pickup run I came upon a brilliant solution! I enlisted the help of my daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; tempted to go with the first suggestion of my youngest, CoolerMomThanYours. (Actually, she insisted I should spell it CoolerMomThanYurs.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, what mom wouldn't love that? But we kept at it and we finally came up with one we all liked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New face of the blog coming soon at MomBehindTheCurtain.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you still need domain hosting, I've been very happy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluehost.com/track/esivy&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bluehost&lt;/a&gt;. You can buy your domain name there too. I'm an affiliate which means that I make a small commission if you click through my link, at absolutely no cost to you. This post also some other links that are affiliate links of other resources I've used, at no cost to you.Thanks for supporting this blog in this way!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*And here's that list I promised of my top mommy blogs or lifestyle blogs with the best names to give you some inspiration for your own blog name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mycrazygoodlife.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My Crazy Good Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unskinnyboppy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unskinny Boppy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mylifeandkids.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My Life and Kids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livingwellspendingless.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Living Well Spending Less&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imaginationsoup.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Imagination Soup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adventuroo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adventuroo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mycrazyeverafter.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My Crazy Ever After&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.delightful.life/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Delightful Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thebigmamablog.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Big Mama&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Melanie has a funny story about her blog name &lt;a href=&quot;http://thebigmamablog.com/about-me/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thepioneerwoman.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Pioneer Woman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thenester.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nesting Place&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.younghouselove.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Young House Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ES Ivy</name></author><summary type="html">It can be tricky to pick a domain name for a lifestyle blog. I like the terms &quot;lifestyle blog&quot; or &quot;mommy blog&quot; because the topics can be so broad on them, which is what has turned out to happen here in my little corner of the internet. But in some ways, that seems to make coming up with a domain name and buying a URL&amp;nbsp;more difficult. But before I get into all that, maybe your wondering - Exactly what is a domain name? And if you look on the internet (like I did), it will become clear to you that all of the definitions were written by software engineers who knew&amp;nbsp;exactly what they were talking about. But after you read their three paragraph definition you'll have no clue what they're talking about. Here's a simple way to define domain name. Look at that string of letters in your browser bar. That's this webpage's URL. (On this webpage right now you should see http://localhost/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog.&amp;nbsp;It will change after I switch over to my new domain name.) A simple way to define URL is the address of a webpage on the internet. The domain name is part of the webpage's URL; it's the &quot;title&quot; or &quot;name&quot; that comes immediately after either &quot;http://&quot; or &quot;www.&quot;, before the next dot back-slash (/). As I write this post, the domain name for this website is esivy.com. You can see it in the URL for this webpage in your browser bar at the top of this page which I've copied below: http://esivy.com/picking-a-domain-name-for-a-lifestyle-blog If you go to the homepage of a website, like Amazon homepage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;www.amazon.com, you'll see only the domain name in the browser bar. If you go to another page on the website, like this one for Miri Attwater and the Oceans' Secret, after the&amp;nbsp;domain name you'll see bunch of other letters or numbers to give the address for that specific webpage&amp;nbsp;on the website&amp;nbsp;Amazon.com. So, now back to choosing a domain name for a lifestyle blog. Why come up with a clever domain name for the URL of a blog? It seems like the title bar on this webpage has had &quot;creative tagline in the works for here&quot; for ages.&amp;nbsp;I've done lots of thinking and brainstorming trying to come up with a blog name. I've read on the internet: How to choose a domain name by Amy Lynn Andrews 4 Things to Consider When Choosing Your Domain Name by ProBlogger And I've read books: Everything&amp;nbsp;But the Posts How to Blog for Profit: Without Selling Your Soul (disclaimer, I am a&amp;nbsp;long way from that profit part) I looked for inspiration from parenting, mommy and lifestyle blog s with names I like. (Surprisingly, if you search for &quot;top mommy blogs&quot; or &quot;best lifestyle blogs&quot; you'll come up with nothing that's useful. Nada. Zilch. So I'll include a list of the best lifestyle blogs with names I like at the end of this post.) But the perfect domain name was elusive. A few months ago, I gave up. I took comfort in the fact that lots of blogs were starting to just use the names of their author. But, I did notice that while I've learned some bloggers' names, I'm more likely to remember a clever blog URL the first time I encounter it. I'm going to be making the switch soon to the Genesis platform, and while I was researching it I came across the new lifestyle blog, MyCrazyEverAfter.com. So clever. So easy to remember. So I was once again inspired to brainstorm. And then, while I did my after-school pickup run I came upon a brilliant solution! I enlisted the help of my daughters. I was really tempted to go with the first suggestion of my youngest, CoolerMomThanYours. (Actually, she insisted I should spell it CoolerMomThanYurs.) I mean, what mom wouldn't love that? But we kept at it and we finally came up with one we all liked! New face of the blog coming soon at MomBehindTheCurtain.com. If you still need domain hosting, I've been very happy at Bluehost. You can buy your domain name there too. I'm an affiliate which means that I make a small commission if you click through my link, at absolutely no cost to you. This post also some other links that are affiliate links of other resources I've used, at no cost to you.Thanks for supporting this blog in this way!&amp;nbsp; *And here's that list I promised of my top mommy blogs or lifestyle blogs with the best names to give you some inspiration for your own blog name. My Crazy Good Life Unskinny Boppy My Life and Kids Living Well Spending Less Imagination Soup Adventuroo My Crazy Ever After The Delightful Life Big Mama&amp;nbsp;(Melanie has a funny story about her blog name here.) The Pioneer Woman Nesting Place Young House Love &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry></feed>